喂
It's me.
是我 我知道你不想跟我共处一室
I know you can 't stand to see me.
我想用电话跟你道歉…
I'm trying to apologize over the phone
我不该亲你的女朋友…
I shouldn't have kissed your girlfriend
别再打来了
Stop calling!
这里是92.3摇滚广播电台
This is 92.3 WXRK,K-Rock...
您是今天的千元挑战者
...calling with our $ 1000 daily challenge!
漂亮
All right!
请问你那位非常抱歉 愿意为你做任何事的室友叫什么名字？
What is the name of your roommate who is very sorry and would do anything?
钱德，别再打来了
-Damn it,Chandler,stop calling.
乔伊，我是罗斯
-Joey,it's Ross.
对不起 没关系
-Sorry. -It's all right.
什么事？ 也没什么
What's up?Not much.
钱德在我这边，他非常非常…
I got Chandler here and he's really,really sorry
本集播出：箱子中的钱德
The One with Chandler in a Box
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
火鸡…说谢谢
Oh,turkey!Giving thanks!
看，这就是感恩节的精神
Look,everyone. It's the spirit of Thanksgiving!
你跟乔伊好一点了吗？
Are things with Joey better?
糟到不能再糟
They couldn't be worse.
我昨晚打了8小时电话给他 想让他跟我说上一句话
I spent eight hours calling him trying to get him to talk to me.
8小时
Eight hours.
你应该用得上入耳式的手机耳机吧？
You could probably use a plug-in telephone headset.
我们会收到 你从公司偷来的圣诞礼物吗？
Should we all expect Christmas gifts that are stolen from your office?
你不会
You shouldn't.
讲到圣诞节
Speaking of Christmas....
莫妮卡和我刚开业，没有钱
Since Monica and I are starting a new business and have no money...
今年就用“秘密圣诞老人”的方法抽签互送吧
...this year we could do Secret Santa
这样只要买一份礼物 还可以猜猜看谁抽到谁
and each only buy one gift.And there's the added mystery of who gets who.
谁抽到“哪个人”
Who gets whom.
我不知道我为什么这么做
I don't know why I do that.
但那样才合文法
But it is correct.
这是什么？
Hey,what's this?
是你们的名字！来抽吧
It's all of your names.Let's pick.
你们在…
Hey,what's going?
乔伊，不要走
-No,Joey,stay.
乔伊，快来，我们要抽签送礼物
We're picking names for Secret Santa.
好啦
Okay.
“秘密圣诞老人”是我发明的
I invented Secret Santa,you know.
你笑什么？
What are you laughing at?
你也说《虎胆龙威》是你的构想
You're the one who said Die Hard was your idea.
本来就是
It was.
别逼我把纸巾拿出来（意即这也是他的创意）
Don't make me show you the napkin.
我要去打个盹，火鸡让我想睡觉
I'm going to take a nap. Turkey makes me sleepy.
还没吃耶
We haven't eaten yet.
我知道，但你那堆准备过程…
I know,but all that work you're doing to get it ready and....
你们有人抽到瑞秋吗？我要换
Did you pick Rachel for your Secret Santa? I'll trade for her.
我抽到她，幸好你要她
I picked her. Thank God,you want her!
你为什么这么想换掉她？
Why do you want to get rid of her so badly?
因为她收到什么都拿去换 要让她满意根本不可能
She exchanges every gift she gets.It's impossible to get her something she likes.
来换吧
Come on,let's trade!
哪有这回事 她很喜欢我送她的背包
I got her that backpack and she loved it.
有只大狗把它叼走时 她哭得好…
I remember she cried when that big dog ran off with
没有什么大狗
There was no big dog.
太讨厌了，我已经为她买了个包还拿去烫了RG
This sucks! I already got her a briefcase with "R.G." put on it.
她的姓名缩写
Her initials.
我很不会认缩写
Okay,I'm really bad at initials.
你今年礼物买得真早
You got your shopping done early.
我的骆驼香烟的兑奖卷快过期了
Yeah,well,my Camel Cash was about to expire.
也许你可以送给别人
Maybe you can give it to somebody else.
像罗斯盖勒（缩写亦为RG）
Like Ross Geller!
那是个女用公事包
You know what? It's a girlie briefcase.
那又怎样，他在博物馆上班
Who cares! He works in a museum.
现在几点？球赛要开始了
The big game's about to start!
不必装了
You don’t have to do that
罗斯乔伊不在，你可以看游行 谢了
Ross and Joey aren't here. You can watch the parade if you want.Thanks.
这个冰箱怎么搞的
What is wrong with this freezer?
怎么了？ 我的眼睛被冰扎到
-What happened? -lce just got in my eye!
这里有人要睡觉
People are trying to sleep in here!
莫妮卡的眼睛被冰扎到很痛
Monica got ice in her eye and it hurts!
张开让我看看 不行，真的很痛
-Open it up. Let me see. -I can't. It really kills.
也许你应该冰敷
Maybe you should put some ice on it.
好像很严重 去看医生好了
-lt looks bad. -We should take you to a doctor.
不行，我的眼科医生是理查
No,my eye doctor is Richard!
我没有男朋友不能去见他
I can't go to him when I don't have a boyfriend.
他对他的病人还真挑剔
He's really picky about his patients.
你非去不可 他的诊所电话几号？
You've got to go. What's his office number?
我哪会记得
Like I remember his office number!
速拨键七
Speed dial seven.
喂，我代表莫妮卡盖勒的眼睛
I'm calling on behalf of Monica Geller's eye.
理查柏克今天在吗？
Is Richard Burke in today?
他不在，她愿意看候诊医师吗
He's not in. Will she see the on-call doctor?
愿意！ 愿意！她非常兴奋
-Yes. -She's very excited about that!
好，我们马上过去
Okay,we'll be right in.
谁要带她去？
Okay,so who's gonna take her in?
我去，你去看游行
I'll go,you can watch your parade.
酷毙了 莫妮卡回来之前，我是主厨
It's so cool. Till Monica gets back,I'm head chef.
我可以做决定
And I get to make all the decisions.
她叫你完全照食谱来
She told you to follow the recipe exactly.
滚出我的厨房
Get out of my kitchen.
好，我跟乔伊有进展了
I think I'm making some progress with Joey.
我进门时，他走进他的房间 但只摔了一次门
When I walked in,he went to his bedroom...but he only slammed the door once.
不过摔的时候有对我竖中指
Yeah,he gave me the finger while doing it.
我得问我妈左手烹饪的问题
I've got to call my mom and ask her a left-handed cooking question.
我要进房里去 我不在的时候…
I'm gonna be in there.While I'm gone....
钱德，你负责
Chandler,you're in charge.
我抽到莫妮卡
I picked Monica for Secret Santa,
但我已经替她买了光明节礼物 你想换吗？
but I'm getting her something for Hanukkah.You want to switch?
其实我想换成你
I was trying to trade...for you.
真的？真好，你要送我什么？
Really? That's so nice. What are you getting me?
不晓得，RG 某种女性化的上班用品吧
I don't know,R.G. I was thinking something girlie for your office.
也许菲比会跟我换
Maybe Phoebe will switch with me.
最好不要，那你会抽到瑞秋 她什么礼物都拿去换
Then you'll get stuck with Rachel,and she exchanges every gift.
乱讲 我送她很多东西她都没退
No,I got her lots of stuff she never took back.
像什么？
Like?
像我去年送她的金项链
Like that gold necklace I got her last year.
她上次戴是什么时候？
When did she wear it last?
她圣诞节整天都戴着，然后…
She wore it all Christmas day and then....
大狗？
Big dog?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
把钱德因内疚买的东西退回去
Sending back this stuff Chandler bought.
全部？包括电视？
-Even the TV?
不，电视要搬进我房里
-No,I'll put that in my room.
乔伊，我知道他做错了
Listen,Joey. I know what he did was wrong.
但你就不能听他解释吗？
But can't you hear him out?
话说回来，当你和瑞秋在一起时
Back when you and Rachel were together,
要是钱德吻了她 你会听他解释吗？
If Chandler had kissed her,would you hear him out?
说得好
That's a good point.
那你要罚他多久？ 5年
How long you going to punish him?Five years.
你还判了刑？ 不敢当就不要做
You've sentenced him?Don't do the crime if you can't do the time.
他是你最要好的朋友 那是以前
The guy's your best friend.Was my best friend.
你干嘛拼命替他说情？
I don't know why you're pushing for him.
少了他碍事 我就没有最要好的朋友了？
With him out of the way as my best friend,there's a spot open.
我吗？ 对
-Who,me? -Yeah.
我真荣幸 你知道我作为朋友首先要做什么？
I'm honored. You know what I'm going to do as your best friend?
拉你去跟钱德说话
I'm going to get you to talk to Chandler.
好啦
All right.
若非你是我最好的朋友…
But if you weren't my best friend....
天哪，真的那么严重？
Oh,my God. Is it really that bad?
我进了门，他根本不理我
I walk in the room,and he won't talk to me.
只念了几句意大利文
He just mumbles something in ltalian.
我知道他只会脏话
And I know he only knows the bad words.
真对不起，都是我不好
I'm so,so sorry. I feel responsible.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
甘瑟，你有看见钱德吗？
-Gunther,have you seen Chandler?
我一直以为你是钱德
-I thought you were Chandler.
你们其中一个在那边
But one of you is over there.
乔伊
Hey,Joe.
（意大利文）
我马上就好 谢谢你温迪
I'll be right with you. Thanks,Wendy.
天哪，这个候诊医生真帅
Oh,my God! How cute is the on-call doctor?
帅到我想拿笔插我的眼睛
So cute that I'm thinking about jamming this pen in my eye.
你的眼科医生缘真好 我知道
-You have the best luck with eye doctors. -I know.
柏克医生可以见你了
Dr. Burke will see you now.
不是柏克医生，柏克医生不在 是候诊医生要帮我看
Oh no-no-no, not Dr. Burke. Dr. Burke is out of town. The-the on-call doctor will see me now.
理查柏克医生不在 他儿子提摩西柏克医生帮你看
Dr. Richard Burke is out.Dr. Timothy Burke,his son,will see you now.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
对不起，刚才…
Hey,I'm sorry. That
你要去哪里？ 我爸妈家
-Where you going? -My folks'.
什么时候回来？
When you coming back?
不知道 可能会住几天顺便找房子
I don't know. I might stay there while I look for an apartment.
什么？
What?
原先我以为我们可以谈开来
Yeah, you know at first I thought we could talk about this y’know, work it out,
但是看到你们在一起，我不认为…
Seeing you two together,I don't think I...
你要我说什么？ 说我不见她吗？
What do you want me to say? Should I stop seeing her?
跟她无关，好吗？
It's not about her. Okay?
但看到你们在一起 就让我想起你做的事
But seeing you together reminds me of what you did.
我不跟一个不懂朋友道义的人 住在一起
I won't live with someone who doesn't know what it is to be a friend.
再见
So, I’ll see ya.
我懂朋友道义，只是我搞砸了
I know what it is to be a friend. I screwed up.
对，没错
Yeah,you did.
所以我要离开
And that's why I'm leaving.
你不为我留下来 至少为它们留下来
If you're not going to stay for me,then at least stay for them.
它们这1年很不顺，还被抢
They had a very difficult year. What with the robbery and all.
小鸡本来很可爱的
And that chick used to be very cute.
当那个人抢了我们 我在柜子里关了6小时
When that guy was robbing us...and I was locked in the entertainment unit for six hours...
你知道我在做什么？ 我在想我太让你失望了
...do you know what I was doing in there all the time?I was thinking about how I let you down.
对，早知道你会见色忘友 我根本不会担心
If I knew what kind of friend you'd be,I wouldn't have worried.
再见
See you around!
等一下…一定有什么我能做的
Wait one second! There has to be something that I can do.
如果柜子还在，我会关6小时 检讨我有多让你失望
If we still had that unit....I'd get in it for six hours and think about how I let you down.
怎么了？
What?
我们有一个箱子
We got a box.
我记得上次见到你 是去上大学的早上
I remember the last time I saw you.It was the morning I left for college.
你站在奶品皇后乳品店外面
You were standing outside the Dairy Queen.
八成是在等它开店
Just probably waiting for it to open.
你现在好漂亮 你也很帅
-You look great now. -You look great too.
你真是个好病人
You're an excellent patient.
情况如何？
How does it look?
你的角膜有刮伤 得戴几天眼罩
You have a scratch on your cornea. You have to wear a patch.
像海盗那样？
Like a pirate?
如果你非要这么说的话
If that helps you.
你跟着你爸多久了？
How long have you been working with your dad?
总得有人提到他
Come on,one of us had to mention him.
我是2个月前搬回来的
I moved back here a couple months ago.
晚上要家庭聚餐？
Big family dinner tonight?
不会吧
No way!
我本来要去女朋友家过感恩节的
I was gonna have Thanksgiving at my girlfriend's.
但我们分手了
But we broke up.
她还不想定下来
She wasn't ready for a serious commitment.
所以你把她推下海了，是吧，水手？
So you made her walk the plank,aye,matey?
你还没戴眼罩呢
You're not wearing the patch yet.
我知道
I know.
他要来过感恩节？
-He's coming here for Thanksgiving?
对啊，好变态喔
-I know. It's sick.
为什么变态？ 因为他是理查的儿子
-Why is it sick? -It's Richard's son!
这跟找希腊悲剧来吃饭一样
It's like inviting a Greek tragedy over for dinner.
如果是希腊人，我会把两只眼睛都弄瞎
If it were Greek,I'd be blind in both eyes.
我喜欢他的英俊、体帖 聪明和…英俊
I like him because he's handsome and he's nice and smart and handsome.
菲比，你了解吧？
Phoebe,you understand,don't you?
我知道你为什么拿我当挡箭牌 但是不行
I could see where I'd be your best shot,but no.
对不起，我觉得很畸形
Sorry,honey. I think it's twisted.
什么事畸形？ 我跟理查的儿子交往
-What's twisted? -Me going out with Richard's son.
我觉得实在不太好
It sounds like a really bad idea to me.
他这样可以吗？ 他好得很
-ls he okay in there? -He's fine!
要是你跟理查的儿子有结果 你就可以告诉孩子
If things work out between you and Richard's son....you can tell your kids...
你跟他们的爷爷上过床
...that you slept with their grandfather.
随你们怎么批评
Judge all you want to.
娶到女同志，临阵逃婚 爱上同性恋冰上舞者
Married a lesbian,left a man at the altar,loved a gay ice dancer
把女生的木腿丢进火里 关在箱子里
...threw a girl's wooden leg in the fire,live in a box!
关箱子的用意到底何在？ 钱德
What exactly is the point of the box?
有三重意义
The meaning of the box is threefold.
第一，让我有时间反省
One,it gives me the time to think about what I did.
第二，证明我有多重视 跟乔伊的友谊
Two,it proves how much I care about my friendship with Joey.
第三…会痛
And three...it hurts.
他关在里面，你们就能和好？
And if he stays in the box you guys will be friends again?
这是个开始
Let's just say it's a start.
记得我去年送你的项链吗？ 可以给我看吗？
Remember that necklace I gave you last year?Can I see it?
为什么？ 我只是想看一下
Why?I just want to check something.
好
Okay.
等着瞧吧
Now we'll see.
气孔！气孔
Air hole! Air hole!
在这里，我很喜欢，我常戴
Here it is. I love it. I wear it all the time.
我送的是金项链，这是银的
The necklace I got you was gold. This is silver.
也许它…变了
Well,maybe...it changed.
天哪，你真的拿去换
Oh,my God! You actually exchanged it.
换一个我喜欢又常用的东西 不是更有用吗？
Isn't it better to exchange it for something I enjoy...and can use a lot?
你换了什么？ 银行存款
What did you get?Credit.
我来开我来开…
I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it. I'll get it.
提姆
Hi,Tim.
谢谢，来见我的朋友
Thank you. Come meet my friends.
这是菲比 幸会
Phoebe.
乔伊 你好
And Joey.
我哥哥罗斯 你好
My brother,Ross.
还有瑞秋
And Rachel.
那是钱德 你好
That's Chandler.How do you do?
这是… 他在…
-What's? -Well,he's....
他在反省
He's doing some thinking.
怎么了？ 你亲了我的女朋友
-What happened? -You kissed my girlfriend!
我喜欢那个墨镜
I like those sunglasses.
是喜欢的喜欢 还是可以换成存款的喜欢
"Like them" like them? Or "I'd like to get store credit" like them?
（意大利文）
各位，火鸡上桌了
This turkey is ready.
哪里可以洗手？ 来…我带你去
Where can I wash up?Let me show you.
毛巾挂在洗手台旁边
The towels are hanging next to the sink.
你可以用高级香皂 谢谢
-And you can use the fancy soap. -Thank you.
高级香皂？ 我以为要留给教皇用
Fancy soap? I thought we were saving that for the pope.
他人很好吧？
See. He's nice,right?
但你真的想在谈恋爱时说
Do you want a relationship where you can actually say:
“这跟你爸常用的做法不同”？
"That's not how your dad used to do it"?
看起来好好吃，我坐哪里？ 我帮你留了
Everything looks great. Where should I sit?Saved you a seat.
变态变态变态变态
Sick,sick,sick,sick.
我去开
I'll get it.
骗到你了
Got you!
这听起来不像是反省
That doesn't sound like thinking to me.
对不起 你不应该说话
-Sorry! -You shouldn't be talking at all.
你要想的太多了 不该说话开玩笑
You've got too much thinking to do to be talking and joking.
好，没问题
Okay,you got it!
罗斯，把蕃薯给我
Ross,pass me the yams?
好，你想换的话 乔伊那里有马铃薯泥
Joey's got the mashed potatoes if you want to exchange them.
够了，你是怎么搞的？
Will you stop! What's the matter with you?
有客人喔
We've got company.
我没怎么搞的
Nothing's the matter with me.
我不是麻木不仁的人 我也有感觉
I'm not completely devoid of sentiment. I have feelings.
好，很好
Okay,fine.
你们看不到 但我正在露屁股打圆场
You can't see,but I'm breaking the tension by mooning you guys.
听着
All right,look!
如果你把它当成笑话 那就算了
If this is a big joke to you,forget about it.
这对我很重要
This means something to me.
要是对你不重要，你就滚出来 否则你就是待在箱子里的白痴
If it doesn't mean anything to you,then get out of there.Otherwise,you're just an idiot in a box.
你说得对，对不起
You're right. I'm sorry.
这对我非常重要 我想跟你和解
This means a lot to me.I want to be friends again.
我发誓不会再说话了
I swear I won't say another word tonight.
你会当一回事？ 绝对会
-So you'll take this seriously? -Absolutely!
你又说话
That sounds like another word to me.
你会当一回事吗？
Are you going to take this seriously?
很好
Okay!
别说我麻木不仁
Don't say that I have no sentiment.
这是第一次约会的电影票根
This is a movie stub from our first date.
这是你第一次 为我做床上早餐的蛋壳
This eggshell is from the first time you made me breakfast in bed.
这是博物馆的，我们第一次…
This is from the museum,the first time we...
在一起
...were together.
我有时会换礼物 但重要的东西我会留
Maybe I exchange gifts sometimes,but I keep the things that matter.
我不知道该说什么，对不起
I don't know what to say. I'm sorry.
但是…这个不能拿
Though you're not supposed to take these.
它有百万年的历史
It's,like,a million years old.
我们还得派专人去挖
We actually have people looking for that.
我可以抽烟吗？ 担心我会死吗？
-Mind if I smoke? -Care if I die?
开玩笑的，你抽吧
No,I'm just kidding,I'm just kidding. Go ahead,smoke.
老是会卡住 让我来
This always happens.Here,let me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你的眼睛…很漂亮
You have very beautiful...eye.
我朋友都觉得这样很怪 包括箱子里那个？
My friends think this is weird.Even the one in the box?
这样不会很怪吧？
It's not weird,is it?
我原先也觉得会，还差点取消 但其实不会
I thought it would be. I almost canceled,but it really isn't.
我知道 我跟你爸完全是两回事
I know. Me and your dad,that's totally separate.
我完全同意
I totally agree.
我们只是两个…互相吸引的人 对吧？
We're two people who find each other...very attractive.Right?
怎么了？ 没事
-What? -Nothing,nothing.
那个吻不好吗？ 不，很好
No,really. Was that not okay?No,that was good.
那个吻很好
That was a good kiss.
天哪！它让你想到… 别说
-lt reminded you of -Don't say it!
但是有，对吧？ 对！
-lt did,didn't it? -Yes!
天哪！ 我知道
I know!
对不起，我真的很抱歉
God,I am sorry. I am so sorry.
没关系 少了感情疮疤就不叫感恩节
It's okay. It wouldn't be Thanksgiving without a little emotional scarring.
更糟的是，我朋友说得对
You know what's even worse?My friends were right.
最糟的是 我觉得你就像年轻的我妈
You know what's worst for me is you remind me of a younger version of my mom.
听着，我真的很抱歉… 没关系
-I want you to know how sorry I am -It's okay.
我气的是钱德
-Chandler's the one I'm mad at.
我还是很抱歉
-Well,I'm still sorry.
他在吗？ 在箱子里
-ls he here? -ln the box.
钱德？ 他现在不能说话
He can't talk right now.
为什么？怎么了？
Why not? What's going on?
他想表示他很重视乔伊
He's trying to show Joey how much he means to him.
所以窝在箱子里？ 乔伊有他的理由
-By being in a box? -Joey had reasons.
有三重意义
They were threefold.
你不能说话反而让事情好办
You not being able to talk might make this easier.
听我说…
Listen....
听我说 我不想介入两个最要好的朋友
I don't want to be someone who comes between two best friends.
我不忍心看着这件事影响你们 我不想成为罪魁祸首
I can't stand seeing what this is doing to you guys.And I don't want to be the cause of that.
所以我们不该再见面了
I don't think we can see each other anymore.
我要去芝加哥找我妈 我会住一阵子
I'm going to my mom's in Chicago.I'm going to stay there for a while.
这段感情本来会很美好
I think this could have been something really amazing.
但这么做也许最好
But,you know,this is probably for the best.
你懂吗？
You know?
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you.
别了，钱德
Goodbye,Chandler.
把箱子打开啦
Open the box!
什么？ 他还追得上她，快出来啦
What?He can still catch her. Get out of there! Get out of there!
所以… 我们没事啦，出来啦
We're going to be fine. Get out!
真的？ 对，你好好反省过了
You did some real good thinking in there.
这真是…
I mean,this is....
快，你还追得上她
You could still catch her!
神秘圣诞老人祝你圣诞快乐
And merry Christmas from your Secret Santa!
谁抽到钱德？我要换
All right,who got Chandler? Because I need to trade.
他看到她了
He sees her!
他在追她
He's catching up to her.
她看到他了
She sees him!
他们拥抱了
They're hugging!
他在抢她的皮包
He's taking her purse.
那不是他们，我去报警
That's not them.I'll go call the police.
他们在那里
There they are!
快去开房间吧
All right,get a room.